[{"question": "What will be the output of <br>a = [1, 2, 3]; b = 5<br>print(max(*a, b))", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "TypeError: '<' not supported between instances of 'int' and 'list'", "correct": false}, {"answer": "a", "correct": false}, {"answer": "5", "correct": true}, {"answer": "b", "correct": false}], "tag": "python", "lecture_file": "10_min_max"}, {"question": "What will be the output of <br>a = [1, 2, 3]; b = 5<br>print(min(a, b))", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "TypeError: '<' not supported between instances of 'int' and 'list'", "correct": true}, {"answer": "a", "correct": false}, {"answer": "1", "correct": false}, {"answer": "b", "correct": false}], "tag": "python", "lecture_file": "10_min_max"}, {"question": "What will be the output of <br>a = [[1, 2, 3], [-1, -2, -3]]<br>print(np.argmin(a, axis = 1))", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "-3", "correct": false}, {"answer": "[5]", "correct": false}, {"answer": "[0, 2]", "correct": true}, {"answer": "[-1, -2, -3]", "correct": false}], "tag": "numpy", "lecture_file": "10_min_max"}, {"question": "A saddle point is always located at a local minimum and local maximum", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "TRUE", "correct": true}, {"answer": "FALSE", "correct": false}, {"answer": "Only local minimum", "correct": false}, {"answer": "Only local maximum", "correct": false}], "tag": "derivative", "lecture_file": "10_min_max"}, {"question": "Which of the following functions from scipy are useful for finding the minimum", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "minimize", "correct": false}, {"answer": "fmin", "correct": false}, {"answer": "solve_ivp", "correct": false}, {"answer": "All of the above", "correct": true}], "tag": "scipy", "lecture_file": "10_min_max"}, {"question": "Finding the global extrema using scipy.optimize.minimize depends on", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "The initial guess", "correct": false}, {"answer": "The solver method", "correct": false}, {"answer": "Constraints", "correct": false}, {"answer": "All of the above", "correct": true}], "tag": "scipy", "lecture_file": "10_min_max"}, {"question": "Accuracy of finding minima using the graphical method is mainly limited by which of the following factors:<br>a: Computational power available<br>b: Discretization of the function<br>c: Plotting library", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "a", "correct": false}, {"answer": "a, b", "correct": true}, {"answer": "a, b, c", "correct": false}, {"answer": "b, c", "correct": false}], "tag": "derivative", "lecture_file": "10_min_max"}, {"question": "The number of iterations performed by the solver when using <br>sol = minimize(f, guess)<br>can be found with", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "sol.int", "correct": false}, {"answer": "sol.nit", "correct": true}, {"answer": "sol.iter", "correct": false}, {"answer": "len(sol.x)", "correct": false}], "tag": "scipy", "lecture_file": "10_min_max"}, {"question": "If f(x) is discontinous at the point x=a, then", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "There is a global minimum at 'a'", "correct": false}, {"answer": "There is a local maximum at 'a'", "correct": false}, {"answer": "There can be either a local maximum or a local minimum at 'a'", "correct": true}, {"answer": "There is a global maximum at 'a'", "correct": false}], "tag": "derivative", "lecture_file": "10_min_max"}, {"question": "Reducing the spacing (dx) between points to calculate the derivative using scipy.misc.derivative() might result in", "type": "multiple_choice", "answers": [{"answer": "Low accuracy", "correct": false}, {"answer": "High accuracy with a risk of numerical instability", "correct": true}, {"answer": "High accuracy and numerical stability", "correct": false}, {"answer": "Low accuracy and numerical instability", "correct": false}], "tag": "scipy", "lecture_file": "10_min_max"}]